<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strandlines</title>
    <link>https://strandlines.blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Strandlines</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a&gt;Stephen James &lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://strandlines.blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/03/2021_03_03_another_test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/03/2021_03_03_another_test/</guid>
      <description>Another test post | Strandlines</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/03/2021_03_03_test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/03/2021_03_03_test/</guid>
      <description>This is a test post | Strandlines</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/02/2021_03_02_pot_holes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/02/2021_03_02_pot_holes/</guid>
      <description>There is a lane near us running alongside some woodland that is open to the public. It&amp;rsquo;s fair to say the road has seen an increase in traffic over the pandemic, given more people seem to be using the wood for exercise. As a result the already poor road surface has deteriorated badly with several potholes opening up.
A couple of weeks ago I noticed red marker paint around the worst of the holes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/02/28/2021_02_28_warm_enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/02/28/2021_02_28_warm_enough/</guid>
      <description>Warm enough to sit out in the garden with a cup of coffee - always an important marker in the spring. The blue tits are very busy around the nest box, watched them bossing other birds around, doing display flights and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/02/26/2021_02_26_first_chiffchaff/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/02/26/2021_02_26_first_chiffchaff/</guid>
      <description>A frosty start followed by a beautiful sunny day. Heard a chiffchaff - the first spring migrant of the year. Possibly the earliest I&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/02/24/2021_02_24_nextcloud_server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/02/24/2021_02_24_nextcloud_server/</guid>
      <description>Harumph. My Nextcloud server has stopped working. I have had a poke around, and it looks like it may be something to do with the SSL certificate auto-renewing. I get an error message telling me one of the key files is missing. Except it is quite clearly there. This is where my lack of knowledge shows up. When something goes wrong.
I guess this is the challenge for a non-tech person trying to DIY their blog/website/internet experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/02/18/2021_02_18_1335_blog_workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/02/18/2021_02_18_1335_blog_workflow/</guid>
      <description>I have now created a basic website for the blog using Hugo. I&amp;rsquo;ve gone the GitHub/Netlify route so have a local repository on the Raspberry pi which I can then push to GitHub. Netlify then automatically deploys the site. I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to redirect my domain there and will hold off from doing so while I do further tinkering.
I had wondered how I would go about posting to the site, so I spent some time last weekend fiddling around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/02/15/2021_02_15_0922_cold_snap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/02/15/2021_02_15_0922_cold_snap/</guid>
      <description>So that&amp;rsquo;s the end of the cold snap. It is so different out there this morning - calm, misty and a positively balmy 9C.
Over the last couple of days the cold weather has emboldened the birds again and this time a song thrush came to the bird table. They do come into the garden frequently but I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen one come this close to the house.
It was very cautious initially, spending a lot of time looking around before dipping its head to take some food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/02/14/2021_02_14_0707_eng_v_ind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/02/14/2021_02_14_0707_eng_v_ind/</guid>
      <description>Eng v Ind. Having seen how much turn there was on day 1 you know it&amp;rsquo;s going to be hard for England batting 2nd. And is it just. India are having their day - Ashwin&amp;rsquo;s bowling of Stokes was superb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/02/06/2021-02-06-1102-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 08:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/02/06/2021-02-06-1102-2/</guid>
      <description>Having got up at 4am for the start of the Eng v Ind test yesterday, it’s too much of a stretch to do so again today. Root is looking very relaxed out there, on 182 as I write this. Top of his game. 🏏</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1100-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 07:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1100-2/</guid>
      <description>It’s blowy, wet and cold out there this morning. But I could hear a blackbird singing. First one of the year. And not it’s winter sub-song but the full-phrase version.
So while it’s still winter in that damp way we seem to specialise in here, you can hear spring coming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1097-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 13:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1097-2/</guid>
      <description>Watched the first episode of Lupin. I’m always a sucker for a good heist story and thoroughly enjoyed it. Netflix automatically started showing it in the English dubbed version but I much preferred it in the original French with subtitles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1095-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 16:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1095-2/</guid>
      <description>A couple centimetres of snow this morning. Funny how that completely changes the dynamic of the bird interactions at our feeders. As a rule each species tends to keep a respectful distance from each other. The sparrows are a boisterous lot and are generally a bit much for the blue tits. But then the robins usually see off the sparrows, and pretty much anyone else. Today, particularly on the table where we put old apples and bird seed, they were all piling in, the need for food taking precedence over any kind of hierarchy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1093-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 10:37:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1093-2/</guid>
      <description>The sun is out and I’ve got Test Match Special on the radio, listening to Eng v Sri Lanka. If I ignore the just-above-zero temperature and the possibility of snow later on, I could almost imagine it’s summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1091-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 19:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1091-2/</guid>
      <description>The hosting for my blog is up for renewal in a month or so. It occurred to me to look into the viability of using the raspberry pi as the web server, making it a truly self-hosted blog.
From what I’ve read it should be ok for a site that doesn’t have much traffic - that’s definitely mine! I will try setting up a dummy site before making it live, probably using a ‘flat file’ type cms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1089-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 19:23:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1089-2/</guid>
      <description>Good to see Michael Rosen is back broadcasting again after having Covid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1086-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 11:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1086-2/</guid>
      <description>Am a bit shocked to discover I have put on weight over the past year. Not that I am overweight buy any means, but given I am pretty active and have a healthy diet in terms of types of food, I have been quite clearly just eating too much. Having acquired a Garmin fitness watch a year ago and made an effort to maintain and improve my fitness it’s not so nice to see I have taken a retrograde step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1084-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 21:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1084-2/</guid>
      <description>Got our son’s gear for school sorted out today, all with half an ear on the news waiting for the almost inevitable closure. Got a ‘welcome back’ email from his headteacher this morning. Just received the ‘school closure’ one a short while ago. I bet she wrote both at the same time….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1082-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 08:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1082-2/</guid>
      <description>Glad I cleaned out one of the nest boxes a few days ago as a blue tit has been having a look already. Better get the others done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1080-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 14:13:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1080-2/</guid>
      <description>More fiddling around with the Raspberry pi over the break. Managed to add an SSL certificate to the Nextcloud server using Certbot which has very easy to use instructions on the website. Next on the list is to learn about and implement some Bash scripts and cron jobs so that I can have to pi doing regular back-ups and such.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1078-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 15:03:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1078-2/</guid>
      <description>Somerset has been moved into tier 4 from today so the few tentative plans to meet with friends have been shelved.
This morning we went to Sainsbury’s to collect our groceries. It’s the first time we’ve done click &amp;amp; collect for the food shopping - we get our thrills where we can in our brave new Covid world. Curiously, the arrangement is to rendezvous with a Sainsbury’s delivery van in a corner of their own car park, as if some shady deal is going down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1075-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 06:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1075-2/</guid>
      <description>Finished The City &amp;amp; the City by China Miéville.
This first came to my attention via the 2018 mini-series based on it. It’s as much, if not more, about its ideas as it is about the plot. I will think about it for a long time. Will read again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1073-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 13:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1073-2/</guid>
      <description>Most of the current affairs podcasts I listen to have released their usual year-in-review episodes. Strangely, I don’t have the slightest urge to listen to any of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1070-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 19:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1070-2/</guid>
      <description>I’ve done some further twiddling, port forwarding on the router and such like and my Raspberry pi Nextcloud server is now accessible remotely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1068-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 13:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1068-2/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday I set up a self-hosted Nextcloud server on the Raspberry Pi, using a spare USB flash drive for storage. This tutorial made it a relatively easy process to do, for a non-tech person, although I did make an error along the way that required going through and checking everything a couple of times.
I can now access the files stored on the server from my home network. Next stop, set up remote access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1064-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 08:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1064-2/</guid>
      <description>In case you wake up wondering where Voyagers 1 and 2 are currently located, NASA has this handy mission status page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1062-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 19:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1062-2/</guid>
      <description>Work/eat/sleep and repeat. That’s what the last two weeks have felt like. It’s always like this for these darkest weeks of the year. There have been a few sunny days, or part days, but also a lot of murk. Days without form or void.
I don’t much like driving at this time of year. Dazzling headlights, spray and poor visibility make it hard work. An hour’s drive in thick fog on Monday was not fun at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1060-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 07:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1060-2/</guid>
      <description>Time I closed some tabs methinks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1058-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 09:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1058-2/</guid>
      <description>I came over here to do something, realised I needed a thing so I could do the something, went off to get the thing, but on the way forgot what it was I was going to get.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1056-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 06:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1056-2/</guid>
      <description>I’ve got up far too early for a Sunday. For any day, come to that. I decided it would be a good idea to set up the Xbox in advance of Christmas and load a couple of games onto it. Mainly so the process doesn’t dominate Christmas Day. That way, it can be presented to my son ‘oven ready’, to use a topical phrase, only in the case of the Xbox, it may actually be true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1053-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 18:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1053-2/</guid>
      <description>Booted up the Raspberry Pi this afternoon for the first time. Used a redundant monitor, keyboard and mouse. It feels good to repurpose old gear that is sitting around unused. I’ve also set up VNC so I can use my iPad as a monitor.
For the time being I’ve loaded Raspbian and I’ll probably keep it this way for the time being while I get used to using it. However, I’ve no doubt that I will fairly quickly get around to wanting to try some other setups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1051-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 06:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1051-2/</guid>
      <description>Spending a fair amount of time each day since Tuesday trying to sort out problems with our business email is not my idea of fun. But I think we are there now.
I thought it was a simple case of updating the DNS records. Which was part of the problem. Exacerbated by being given the incorrect information maybe four times? In the end it transpired the DNS records were correct. The problem was, for reasons beyond my comprehension of these things, the hosting company’s firewall was blocking my IP address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1049-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 20:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1049-2/</guid>
      <description>I’m not entirely sure what my plans for it are yet, but this Raspberry Pi 4 arrived yesterday. My new toy to tinker with over the long nights of winter. Mess around with Linux? Make a Minecraft server? Lots of possibilities and a few ideas in the pipeline. Goodbye boredom….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1044-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 15:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1044-2/</guid>
      <description>I’ve just emerged from a JavaScript rabbit hole. I’ve been writing a script that, combined with Shortcuts, will regularly do a backup of a text file. It is probably inelegant, but it works and as a JavaScript newbie I’m feeling pretty good about it.
This all came about due to my increasing dissatisfaction with Apple and tech in general, or more specifically, the business model that much of tech is based on, namely built-in obsolescence and the lack of control over individual’s data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1042-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 07:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1042-2/</guid>
      <description>Tonight I am picking up an Xbox One S for my 11yr old. Just for him. The only reason I am also getting Red Dead Redemption 2 is so that _I _can test the Xbox works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1040-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 07:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1040-2/</guid>
      <description>In light of recent events across the pond, it has been good to experience the feeling that not everything is wrong with the world. Not that everything is right, not by a long shot. But to be reminded of what it used to feel like, to have hope, to believe in our future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1038-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 08:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1038-2/</guid>
      <description>Automations on iOS 14 are so much better now that they can be set up to run, er, automatically.
Except when they don’t. Run at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1036-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 13:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1036-2/</guid>
      <description>Why have I not come across Todo.txt before? As a .txt file zealot an&amp;rsquo; all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1031-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 18:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1031-2/</guid>
      <description>A day off for my wife and I and a lovely one at that. A walk in Wiltshire followed by cooking up lunch in the van. Very grateful for it to have coincided with such good weather and autumn colours. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1028-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 05:11:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1028-2/</guid>
      <description>Had a long chat with the Aged Parents about their moving plans and contrary to my concerns they seem to be taking a more realistic and pragmatic approach to things. It’s strange, edging closer to being a carer, not that they need ‘care’ as such yet, but greater involvement is going to become the norm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1012-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 06:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1012-2/</guid>
      <description>I’m glad it’s the weekend and I can have a lie in. This last week was supposed to be straightforward but haha, not so.
Thursday afternoon, I had an unexpected change to my day which threw the good old anxiety into overdrive. The first time in a while that I have had such a big reaction and it left me exhausted. It all ran over into Friday where every small thing seemed imbued with far greater stress and significance than was really the case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1010-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 12:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1010-2/</guid>
      <description>Last night, the Tories voted down Labour’s motion to extend free school meals during the holidays to disadvantaged children. My son enjoys maths so this morning we did a rough calculation to find out the cost to the Treasury of the scheme, had it been voted through.
According to this article in the Guardian, it would affect 1.4 million children. The vouchers are worth £15 per week, and there are four weeks holiday between now and Easter, which is when it was proposed the scheme would run until.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1006-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 04:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1006-2/</guid>
      <description>Had a problem with the contact form on our business’s website. Loads of spam plus genuine contacts were being labelled as spam too. In looking to solve this I considered using Captcha. In reading about it I discovered it’s a Google thing and, unsurprisingly, collects a lot of data.
So I won’t be installing that then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/1003-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 14:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/1003-2/</guid>
      <description>One morning this last week I stepped outside at first light. It was very still and quiet. My attention was drawn to the sound of redwings overhead. The first I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this autumn. Just a few small flocks but a sure sign of the turning of the seasons. Later on the same day I saw a handful of swallows. Another remnant of summer. Two species who’s combined migratory range extends from Siberia to South Africa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/998-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 12:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/998-2/</guid>
      <description>Back in April I said I’d write about my experience with CBT. And I have tried many times to do so. The Summer of Weirdness has made it very difficult to find the headspace to reflect on anything, let alone something as intense as therapy. I’ve decided it’s just too much to try and go back and unpick my thoughts in detail about it, but for what it’s worth, here’s a brief summary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/995-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 20:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/995-2/</guid>
      <description>One of the reasons I switched to a Wordpress site for my blog was to use the IndieWeb plugin, in particular to enable webmentions. It takes a little more work to implement than a straightforward post but I like being able to do so. The ethos of the IndieWeb has a lot of appeal. Only thing is, I haven’t used them as much as I could.
I have saved links to numerous posts I that I’ve come across on other people’s blogs, with the intention of referencing them in my own posts via webmentions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/993-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 06:54:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/993-2/</guid>
      <description>Shared some of my experiences of anxiety with a close family member yesterday. Feel horribly exposed about even though the conversation went ok. Very much in two minds about the benefit of doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/991-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 13:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/991-2/</guid>
      <description>In the first four days of October we have had two–three times the rainfall that we had throughout the whole of September.
Over the past week we have had the first frost, first evening with the wood burner lit, and the first mornings with the heating on. A small flock of mistle thrushes was in the chestnut tree in the church yard next door - we occasionally see a pair around here, but to see a flock can only mean they are winter migrants from the continent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/989-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 18:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/989-2/</guid>
      <description>The Covid test came back negative, for which I’m pleased. Just over 24hrs from test to result so not bad given some of the stories reported. Just one day of self-isolation and back to normal tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/987-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 07:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/987-2/</guid>
      <description>An unforeseen and quite entertaining byproduct of using a vpn is I now get embedded adverts in the language of where the vpn server is, currently Holland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/985-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 17:45:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/985-2/</guid>
      <description>Started to feel a bit unwell yesterday. Had a high temperature this morning so after checking the NHS website realised I had to go and get a Covid test. Our nearest site was just 40 mins away and meant a very pleasant drive in the autumn sunshine. Had to do the test myself which wasn’t awful, but not very nice either. Just got to self-isolate now, at least until we get the result back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/983-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 13:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/983-2/</guid>
      <description>Feeling pretty pleased having managed to successfully replace the battery in an old iPhone 5S, with the intention of making it my son’s first phone. Done for less then 20 quid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/978-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 15:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/978-2/</guid>
      <description>Went out on the mountain bike this morning, up into the hills. Lovely light. Got to say, exercise seems to be one of the best ways to work off the morning’s cortisol, anxiety and stomach butterflies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/975-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 14:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/975-2/</guid>
      <description>Linking notes in an organised fashion along the lines of a zettelkasten is an idea that appeals, as I make notes and save things to read later all the time. I could do this in Drafts but like Bear notes, another option, the notes are saved in iCloud, and I don&amp;rsquo;t think they are in plaintext or other easy to migrate format. I think it was via Neil Mather that I came across TiddlyWiki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/970-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 11:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/970-2/</guid>
      <description>If I’m honest, I have to admit that part of the reason I will listen to so many podcasts is so I don’t have to listen to the stream of negative horseshit that my mind seems to produce if left to its own devices. Something to work on there, methinks.
~
In the last two days I’ve seen and/or heard kingfishers in two different locations. They do seem to get very vocal at this time of year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/964-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 12:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/964-2/</guid>
      <description>I am grateful to those who can write or speak honestly about their battle with mental illness. The above post from Sameer Vasta popped up in my feed today. It isn&amp;rsquo;t easy to be open about the things that go on in our heads, but what I can say to those who do, it is so valuable. Thank you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/960-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 18:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/960-2/</guid>
      <description>“I wonder,” said the Hon. Freddy Arbuthnot, “what damn silly fool invented Sunday afternoon.”  Dorothy L Sayers Clouds of Witness</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/958-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 09:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/958-2/</guid>
      <description>The swallows have definitely left now, the odd straggler around, possibly the late brood feeding up before leaving. Heard a Little owl during the night, the first I’ve heard this autumn. Various warblers on the move as well: willow warblers, chiffchaffs, and blackcaps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/956-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 05:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/956-2/</guid>
      <description>None</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/953-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 06:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/953-2/</guid>
      <description>It might be my over active imagination, but golden hour seems to be continuing longer after sunrise than I’d normally expect. I wonder if there are enough particulates from the US wildfires in the atmosphere here to cause a noticeable effect?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/948-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 06:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/948-2/</guid>
      <description>Am making the most of watching and listening to our swallows before they depart for South Africa. I shall miss having them around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/946-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 20:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/946-2/</guid>
      <description>In case you wondered….Why wasps become so annoying at the end of summer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/943-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 09:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/943-2/</guid>
      <description>I’m kind of done with Apple. In the sense of being loyal to the ecosystem. I’ve always had a slight reluctance to go all in with their native apps anyway. What if I want to move to a different system at a later date?
Migrating information out of Apple always looks less than ideal. Hence, for example, I like to use a plain text file system for notes, stored in Dropbox, rather than the native Notes app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/940-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 20:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/940-2/</guid>
      <description>Off to see Mum today. Up early, away by 7am. An easy drive and beautiful light. Gold and blue. A skein of geese passing over the motorway.
A much needed conversation. In a good way. Dad’s health, mind and moving forward. Concerns laid bare. Mum feeling looked after.
Practicalities. Sorted a problem with their phone.
Then back home. A different route to avoid the holiday traffic.
Exhausted. But worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/937-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 18:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/937-2/</guid>
      <description>My siblings and I have been using Signal for group chats of late, often about the aged parents. Over the last few days the topic of Dad’s cognitive state has been top of the list, wondering if there is confusion and such starting to show. A few days ago my brother reported a conversation that was markedly scrambled.
For the Bank Holiday weekend we had planned something relaxing. A slow Saturday, meeting up with friends tomorrow, and maybe a day of catching up on some jobs on Monday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/935-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 16:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/935-2/</guid>
      <description>Well done Jimmy, on that 600th wicket! 🏏</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/933-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 08:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/933-2/</guid>
      <description>Am finding that my time spent on meditation seems to be a cue for my brain to run through lists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/931-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 19:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/931-2/</guid>
      <description>None</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/929-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 19:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/929-2/</guid>
      <description>Another walk today, on the chalk hills in Dorset. Managed to dodge the showers. Just over 7k.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/926-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 13:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/926-2/</guid>
      <description>Brian Eno Music for Installations - perfect to drift off to. 🎵</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/923-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 06:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/923-2/</guid>
      <description>171 - what an innings for Zak Crawley so far&amp;hellip;🏏</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/918-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 18:17:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/918-2/</guid>
      <description>Day off today, so we got up early and hoofed it off to Exmoor. Arrived in the fog, cooked up pancakes and then went for a walk in the belated sunshine. Paddled in a stream, cooked up lunch, sat around enjoying the warmth and then wandered home. Feel better for that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/912-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 04:25:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/912-2/</guid>
      <description>Am working my way through the back catalogue of The Hilarious World of Depression podcast.
It’s funny, moving and encouraging. Occasionally, someone says something which really nails it in some way.
John Moe, the host, on moving to a place of recognition and healing;
…there’s a sadness, I think, that comes with feeling healthier, mentally. You uncover some truths, you accept them. And that lets you stop doing all the frantic things you’ve been doing for so many years to run from the problems in your mind, the facades you’ve been putting up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/910-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 20:12:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/910-2/</guid>
      <description>Watched Rogue One for our family Star Wars season - not sure if it’s the second or third time. Love it. The two weird uncanny-valley CGI characters aside, that is. Otherwise everything is right with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/908-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 18:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/908-2/</guid>
      <description>Was awake in the night due to the heat. Heard a curious sound outside. A repeated wheezing call. A bit of research and discovered it was the begging call of juvenile tawny owls. I think there must have been two of them. Good to know ‘our’ tawny’s have successfully reared young this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/906-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 12:23:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/906-2/</guid>
      <description>In regard to taking meds, I’d like to run a control version of myself in parallel so that I can identify what and if the meds are doing anything useful.
I make notes about effects that I attribute to them. I then read the notes later and wonder if they actually have anything to do with the meds at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/904-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 05:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/904-2/</guid>
      <description>Apart from a bit of lightning in the distance last night, am most disappointed to have missed out on the thunderstorms overnight. There is still thundery cloud about this morning, so maybe we’ll be in luck today, however, it’s quite a bit cooler so the chance may have passed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/901-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 19:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/901-2/</guid>
      <description>Read Dissolution by C J Sansom. Already familiar with the story from the BBC radio adaptation, although it’s long enough ago that I listened to it to have forgotten who it was what dunnit.
Set during the time of the dissolution of the monasteries, it’s a conventional but enjoyable and pacy historical murder mystery. Greed, lust, power, class and pond drainage. Somewhat in the vein of Ellis Peters&amp;rsquo; Cadfael series but with more bodily fluids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/897-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 12:55:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/897-2/</guid>
      <description>🎥 As part of our Disney+ summer binge, we watched Star Wars: Episode II - Attack of the Clones  last night. I had not seen it before, not being a dyed-in-the-wool Star Wars fan, but we are working our way through the whole series.
Well, I knew it got some bad reviews and I can see why. I am not going to waste my breath on what I thought was wrong with it other than to say it felt like a lot longer than the 2+ hours running time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/894-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 21:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/894-2/</guid>
      <description>🏏 An enjoyable and gripping match between England and Pakistan. A good win for England and am glad to see Buttler demonstrate why he is in the team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/892-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 19:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/892-2/</guid>
      <description>After a curiously murky and muggy day, I’m glad the skies have cleared. Enjoying sitting outside this evening watching the fading light. It’s very still, the sounds of distant traffic, a few birds and my dog rummaging under the pear tree for fallers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/889-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 04:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/889-2/</guid>
      <description>Have been finding it difficult to write anything of a personal nature at the moment. A few days ago I started writing about how, since the start of the lockdown, I have finally reached a kind of equilibrium. Adaptation to the new normal, at least, the current new normal.
It almost feels like emotional numbness. Maybe it is. While here in the SW we have experienced little of Covid itself, living with the lockdown measures has been a strain, as it has for everyone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/885-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 05:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/885-2/</guid>
      <description>🍿Watched: Murder on the Orient Express. The Kenneth Branagh version.
Sumptuous. Which is what I expect from a Poirot.
And what a moustache.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/883-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 10:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/883-2/</guid>
      <description>Given that everyone in the UK has decided to go camping this year, we are making the most of it and selling surplus camping/van gear on eBay.
It’s a few years since I last sold anything on eBay and I had forgotten about all the emails asking questions …
Can I collect? No, it’s delivery only, like it says in the listing
Can you post it? No, it’s collect only, like it says in the listing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/881-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 05:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/881-2/</guid>
      <description>🏏 A good series win for England yesterday and great to see Stuart Broad has still got it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/879-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 12:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/879-2/</guid>
      <description>Signed up to Disney+ so that we can binge on some stuff over the summer. Might only do it for a couple of months but given my son currently lives and breathes Star Wars, seems like a good idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/877-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 15:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/877-2/</guid>
      <description>After nearly deleting Omnifocus, I paid for a month’s subscription and have been giving some more time to it. But I have also been using Things 3. I bought this for my iPad quite a while ago and enjoyed using it other than it being very date focussed, which doesn’t really suit my style. In addition it doesn’t have an equivalent of perspectives in Omnifocus.
However, since I last used Things, a comprehensive URL scheme has been implemented and this is a game changer, enabling the creation of Shortcuts in IOS that emulate perspectives pretty well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/873-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 19:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/873-2/</guid>
      <description>A bike ride up on the hills with my son and a friend. Somehow managed to time it to coincide with a spell of heavy rain. So warm though and little wind, it didn’t matter. Nice to try out the bike upgrades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/871-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 19:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/871-2/</guid>
      <description>Watched Free Solo again, this time my son watched as well. Alex Honnold makes thought provoking comments throughout the film about fear and dealing with it. Timestamps noted so that I can go through later and jot down the bits that got my attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/868-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 21:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/868-2/</guid>
      <description>Just managed to get a peep at comet Neowise. The sky is still rather light in the NE but Neowise looked good through the binoculars. What is more impressive is Jupiter to the SE. Very bright and visible as a disc through the binoculars and 4 of its moons very clear as well. Blows the mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/866-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 14:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/866-2/</guid>
      <description>While doing the brakes etc on my bike I noticed the rear tyre was in bad shape. Ordered a Maxxis Minion (which amuses my son no end) this week, fitted it this morning. Went for a slightly fatter tyre which should make for a better ride on the rough stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/864-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 06:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/864-2/</guid>
      <description>Watched Free Solo. Thoroughly enjoyed it. Beautifully shot. Am fascinated by stories of people pushing the boundaries of what is physically and mentally possible - an extraordinary feat. Mr Honnold, I salute you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/862-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 06:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/862-2/</guid>
      <description>Took the day off on Monday for a family birthday. Went for a walk in a Wiltshire nature reserve we discovered last year. So very peaceful. Much needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/860-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 21:03:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/860-2/</guid>
      <description>Beautiful mackerel sky this morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/854-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 10:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/854-2/</guid>
      <description>🎵Listening to&amp;hellip;Jon Hopkins - Insides. What a brilliant album. The track Light through the veins sounded familiar. It’s on the intro and outro to Coldplay’s Viva la vida. Turns out Brian Eno, who produced the album, got Jon Hopkins on board as well. Coldplay evidently liked his work!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/852-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 19:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/852-2/</guid>
      <description>Test cricket is back in the UK tomorrow! No crowds, so the absence of the buzz will be strange, but hey, it’s cricket 🏏</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/850-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 12:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/850-2/</guid>
      <description>Further to my plans to fit new brakes on my bike, I ordered some that were suitable, which duly arrived a week or so ago. All good to go.
Only I had not paid attention to the existing brake levers, the ones that are quite literally in front of me when I’m riding. They are combined brake levers/gear shifters….
Why I’d not thought of that before ordering the new ones, I’m not sure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/847-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 17:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/847-2/</guid>
      <description>I have been messing around with OmniFocus. Again.
I tried it maybe a couple of years ago, but couldn’t quite justify committing to it. I think I might be heading the same way again.
I love the perspectives. And the organisation of projects.
But the lack of quick entry of tasks, a la Fantastical or Todoist is probably a deal breaker. And then I discovered that deferred tasks no longer show up in the Forecast view if the start date passes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/845-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 04:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/845-2/</guid>
      <description>I’ve just come out of a particularly long rabbit hole. Have spent the last 10 days or so obsessively learning more about automation and scripting in the context of task managers, URL schemes, Drafts and Shortcuts.
One of those occasions where the enjoyment of discovery meant other things didn’t get my attention, like reading and blogging.
I think my efforts have paid off. I have to get on now and use what I’ve learnt and not just continue trying out more ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/842-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 05:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/842-2/</guid>
      <description>DEVS. Got to episode 5. Don’t think I can be arsed with watching anymore. Too much staring into space, the void, whatever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/838-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 18:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/838-2/</guid>
      <description>The other day, our old boy bumped into a lamp post. His vision is not so good now, as he has cataracts. Along with prodigious eyebrows, as is befitting a dog of his breed and age.
I have a theory that the cataracts diffuse direct sunlight, such that it blurs his vision beyond that which the cataracts do. I once mentioned this to a human who had cataracts (but not prodigious eyebrows) and she bore out my theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/833-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 08:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/833-2/</guid>
      <description>And carrying on with the Wiltshire landscape theme of yesterday’s post, here’s something of a significant discovery made public today…Vast neolithic circle of deep shafts found near Stonehenge | Science | The Guardian</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/828-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 18:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/828-2/</guid>
      <description>Went for a short family walk on the Wiltshire Downs that turned into a respectable 6k. Wildflowers and birds and a big sky. Skylark, whitethroat, blackcap, yellow hammer, corn bunting and willow warbler.
Took this photo from a long barrow. And according to the map, crossed a Roman road. History beneath our feet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/819-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 06:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/819-2/</guid>
      <description>None</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/815-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 18:40:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/815-2/</guid>
      <description>Have been looking at new bikes. I don’t need one. And frankly, finding one I’d want at the moment is not that easy.
My son and I have been cycling more of late. He is on a bigger bike now and is far more capable so that opens up many new possibilities.
I bought my bike secondhand some years ago. It’s a mish-mash of components, some good, some not so good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/813-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 20:47:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/813-2/</guid>
      <description>Rumbles of thunder coming from the north.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/806-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 06:23:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/806-2/</guid>
      <description>Blogging for me is a way to process thoughts. This is mostly an in-out system. Stuff happens, I think about it, I write.
Not everything ends up on the blog. Many sentences jotted down go no further. But things that need working out in more depth will probably end up as a post.
For the last week though, I’ve been in a log-jam. Too much to process.
Statues, protests, police violence, BLM, climate change, coronavirus, those that have, those that don’t, will a relation need cancer treatment, no school until September, how will we manage that, how are my elderly parents really doing, what kind of world is my son growing up in, the van needs a service, I’d like more sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/800-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 12:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/800-2/</guid>
      <description>These 4 young blackbirds in a nest in our garden are not far off leaving. Am sitting outside enjoying a beer, and can hear the noise they all make when a parent brings them food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/785-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 04:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/785-2/</guid>
      <description>None</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/781-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 16:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/781-2/</guid>
      <description>Last year, I was voraciously reading forum posts and articles relating to mental illness. It was the early days after my wake up call and I was trying to learn as much as I could. From time to time I would come across someone voicing the question ‘Where do I end and my mental illness begin?’
It was reassuring to see others express this as it reflected what was going through my mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/773-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 05:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/773-2/</guid>
      <description>Flexibits have removed the annoying pop-up prompts to sign up for the premium version of Fantastical on iOS. It is now much more pleasant to use again. The natural language input is just brilliant and being able to use actions in Drafts for setting up events makes for a really useful workflow.
I am still yet to be convinced that the premium version is worth it, much as I would like to have access to Fantastical on the Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/766-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 06:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/766-2/</guid>
      <description>Switching my Wordpress theme to SemPress recently, I didn’t realise it lacked a search function. The previous theme did and it was handy to have as I have trouble remembering when I wrote something.
So a bit of fiddling to do with the website this weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/762-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 15:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/762-2/</guid>
      <description>The lockdown has given us a pretty unique perspective on what is important and what is not, particularly in terms of how we spend our time.
I am at much the same place as you Colin, and it _feels _like this is a moment in life in which to re-evaluate, an opportunity not to be missed. But as to what to change, and how, I don&amp;rsquo;t know. I hope you find your way&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/758-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 19:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/758-2/</guid>
      <description>Facebook Says Very Little on Privacy of Messenger Rooms
Those policies, and the few specifics Facebook has given publicly about Messenger Rooms, leave unanswered important questions about how the company handles the metadata around video calls… No surprises there, then.
The Facebook “data policy,” which the company spokesperson repeatedly pointed me to as the firm’s canonical document for questions of information collection, is mostly built from vastly generalized statements (“We collect information about how you use our Products”) punctuated by slightly narrowed examples (“such as the types of content you view or engage with”).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/754-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 20:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/754-2/</guid>
      <description>Changed our business email hosting provider over the weekend. A fairly straightforward process other than changing the MX records. Used the live chat support to find out what they need to be changed to. It took nearly an hour for them to do it.
Maybe there was a genuine reason for why it took so long but anyway. Got it sorted eventually. And the new system is a lot easier to manage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/752-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 05:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/752-2/</guid>
      <description>Thoughts have not come easily for the last few days. A flatness in my mind, probably induced in part by a lack of sleep, which in turn is brought on by the short nights and hayfever.
Having finally developed a sense of stability around The Situation for the moment, a kind of ennui has settled in. Not a frame of mind I particularly go for.
This is neither thoroughly unpleasant nor very enjoyable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/750-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 18:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/750-2/</guid>
      <description>Two trips for groceries over the last couple of weeks. Both times - no paella rice, no couscous and no…..rinse aid. Rinse aid? Really don’t get that one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/748-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 08:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/748-2/</guid>
      <description>Two podcast episodes I have enjoyed this week: one old, one new, both related to Roman Mars.
Scientists use the opportunity the world being in lockdown presents to conduct research that would otherwise be impossible… 401- The Natural Experiment - 99% Invisible
And a weird code related quirk… 140 The Roman Mars Mazda Virus - Reply All</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/743-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 19:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/743-2/</guid>
      <description>Heard my first cuckoo of the year. Which presupposes that I will hear more. Quite likely not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/735-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 18:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/735-2/</guid>
      <description>Naomi Klein, writing about how big tech plans to profit from the pandemic, acknowledges that:
technology is most certainly a key part of how we must protect public health in the coming months and years. However, she goes on to ask these vital questions about our relationship with tech:
..will that technology be subject to the disciplines of democracy and public oversight, or will it be rolled out in state-of-exception frenzy, without asking critical questions that will shape our lives for decades to come?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/728-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 14:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/728-2/</guid>
      <description>A family walk this morning. Took a trip out to the Somerset Levels, now that we are allowed to travel a bit more.
Lots of birds - but no cuckoos. Swifts, sedge warblers, curlews, reed buntings, skylarks, egrets and swans.
Meadows looking lovely. Lots of flowers including orchids (Southern Marsh?).
Drama in the garden when we returned. Birds giving alarm calls - turned out a great spotted woodpecker was having a crack at the box where the great tits are nesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/720-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 17:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/720-2/</guid>
      <description>Came across this research paper on social anxiety disorder and one sentence stood out, as it sheds some light on the unresolved question of how can it take so long to realise there is something going on:
Owing to the early onset and chronicity of SAD, many individuals may also believe that these symptoms are part of their personality and therefore cannot be changed. Makes me feel better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/715-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 07:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/715-2/</guid>
      <description>Some apprehension today, as I am expecting it to be busier out and about, on the back of the government’s announcement encouraging a return to work.
I hope, I really do, that people will be considerate and make the effort to social distance themselves in busier places, with more of us around. Most people are considerate, but I’ve seen enough of the small number who aren’t to think it a legitimate concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/713-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 13:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/713-2/</guid>
      <description>None</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/708-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 05:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/708-2/</guid>
      <description>For a bird with a reputation for being secretive, jays make an almighty racket when the occasion calls for it.
Yesterday, a walk in the woods. A jay kicks off in the trees above me. Spotted movement amongst the branches. There it was, getting in the face of a tawny owl. It would fly onto the branch next to the owl, squawk in its face and fly off again. Meanwhile, she would give a little ‘tu-whit’ in response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/702-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 12:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/702-2/</guid>
      <description>The swifts have arrived, screaming of summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/697-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 04:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/697-2/</guid>
      <description>Is there a good source of secondhand books in the UK that isn’t Abebooks? While it is a good website it’s still another part of the Kingdom of Amazon, and I’m trying to avoid all things Bezos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/694-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 06:31:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/694-2/</guid>
      <description>A while back Colin Walker commented on a post of mine:
Mental health awareness has come on in leaps and bounds recently but, for many, that’s still all it is: an awareness. We need to convert that into an understanding.  Fortunately, we are more aware of mental health issues today, certainly compared to how it was when I was growing up. Prior to facing up to my own issues I considered that I had a basic appreciation of what having a mental illness meant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/686-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 11:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/686-2/</guid>
      <description>International Dawn Chorus Day
Got out into the garden this morning to listen to the dawn chorus, and made these two recordings. Stereo recording, best listened to with headphones for full immersion.
First one at 5:15am, mainly blackbirds and robins. It started to rain as I recorded so you can hear that too.
 strandlines · 030520 0515 Dawn Chorus
Second recording, made at 6:00am and the sound profile has changed - many more species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/683-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 19:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/683-2/</guid>
      <description>Finished reading and enjoyed Roadside Picnic by Arkady and Boris Strugatsky. 📚</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/681-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 20:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/681-2/</guid>
      <description>Here in the UK, the guidance on what constitutes a reasonable excuse to leave the house includes ‘driving to countryside and walking (where far more time is spent walking than driving)’. We took this at face value yesterday and drove to a local spot for a 3 mile walk in woodland. It was a lovely day and we enjoyed bluebells and the fresh green of new beech leaves. There were a few other walkers about but everyone was considerate and sensible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/667-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 05:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/667-2/</guid>
      <description>Cryptomnesia /ˌkrɪptəmˈniːzɪə/ • n when I have a great idea or thought only to learn that my wife made the very same suggestion just a few days prior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/664-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 07:58:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/664-2/</guid>
      <description>It is a year ago today since I first recognised something of what was going on with my mental health. It has been a long 12 months, going through various states of mind as I have tried to come to terms with it all.
I haven’t posted much on the subject of late, largely because I have been receiving CBT since January and it is prettty intense. I have now finished the course except for a couple of follow up sessions and it seems a good time to reflect on both the therapy and the last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/659-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 19:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/659-2/</guid>
      <description>Have intended to give sourdough a go for a little while now, so with it being the Thing To Do while we are hunkered down in our vaults, I decided now was the time. Got some great advice from Jeremy Cherfas over at Micro.blog on getting a starter going, so thanks to him.
Started one last weekend and then this weekend made my first loaf. Really quite pleased with it. More dense than I hoped but was even textured and tasted delicious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/655-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 18:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/655-2/</guid>
      <description>About 20 years ago, we went travelling in Canada, and part of our time was spent driving across the prairie in Alberta and Saskatchewan. It is a fascinating landscape and so very different from ours here in the UK. It was also a disconcerting experience, and much as I enjoyed it I also found it oppressive. I put this down to the geography. In the UK you always know more or less where you are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/650-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 18:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/650-2/</guid>
      <description>A walk in the woods&amp;hellip;to see the bluebells. Freshened by this morning’s rain, they seemed to glow with their own internal light source. Trees alive with the songs of blackcaps, chiffchaffs, goldcrests and tree creepers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/643-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 20:44:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/643-2/</guid>
      <description>Tonight I ventured to the supermarket. Two items of note;
 * my wife wrote a shopping list which included 1 block of strength 3 Cheddar cheese, 1 block of strength 4. I misread it and bought 3 blocks and 4 blocks respectively. So inadvertently I have now stockpiled cheese…. * while waiting at the checkout a customer gave the young woman working the till a bunch of flowers, at which she promptly burst into tears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/639-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 08:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/639-2/</guid>
      <description>Watched Bumblebee with the family yesterday. I have zero investment in the Transformers world but thought it very enjoyable. My 10yr old gave it a big thumbs up. Really liked the &amp;lsquo;80s milieu and cultural references. Good to see a female protagonist and thought the CGI was good - the robots had solidity and weight to them. A fun family action film with a lot of heart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/632-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 18:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/632-2/</guid>
      <description>The blue tits that are using the nest box in our garden are getting much busier. Nest building is very much underway as can be seen in the picture below. I built and installed the box last year, and what they don’t know is that it has a hinged roof, so I can take a peek inside. This is not just from idle curiosity but so that I can record the nest activity for the BTO Nest Record Scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/624-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 06:29:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/624-2/</guid>
      <description>As any parent will know, boundaries are there for children to test. And for my 10 year old, that means the physical boundaries - of our garden. Footballs, rugby balls, cricket balls, a space hopper (remember those? Yes, we have one). They all make frequent trips over the fence into our neighbours garden or the field. My 10 year old&amp;rsquo;s power output currently far outstrips his accuracy and control.
Much as it frustrates me at times when I have to go and find a ball for the umpteenth time, I have to remind myself that this testing of the boundaries will stand him in good stead later in life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/619-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 19:54:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/619-2/</guid>
      <description>Some positives from the last week or so&amp;hellip;
For the second time in a week I have seen a peregrine falcon. This one was circling about a hundred metres above me - the heavier build was a give away, distinguishing it from our other falcons and hawks. The white on its face catching the sun as it wheeled, it climbed higher and higher without so much as a flap of the wings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/613-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 19:14:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/613-2/</guid>
      <description>Warm enough to eat outside this evening while enjoying the sight and sound of our newly arrived visitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/610-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 06:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/610-2/</guid>
      <description>A swallow by the Mill when I ran on Sunday am. It was on the wires Mon am. Swallows at the Stourton&amp;rsquo;s yesterday. Watched a couple over our village yesterday evening. Cloudy but mild. Growing weather. Blackcap singing near manor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/605-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 19:26:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/605-2/</guid>
      <description>In order to stay positive, I am trying to limit my intake of news. I want facts, not sensation. Even some of the output from those sources I deem to be more measured have arguably strayed into the unnecessary at times.
I also find decent analysis useful to listen to as well. I have recently subscribed to the podcast Outrage and Optimism. One of the hosts is Christiana Figueres, who led the work at the UN that resulted in the Paris Agreement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/602-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 18:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/602-2/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to read an adventure/mystery novel that was not in the usual thriller or crime genres that I tend to read when I am in the mood for a good yarn. Picked on ‎Labyrinth by Kate Mosse, based on having heard of her and aware her books are popular. Big mistake - what should have been an intriguing mystery was let down by two-dimensional characters and pretty dull writing. I had hoped for an enjoyable if undemanding page turner, but it was not to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/593-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 11:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/593-2/</guid>
      <description>Ran a new route this morning. I needed to increase my distance so worked out new a 4k circuit that took me on some new footpaths. Nice sunny morning - windy but much warmer. Saw my first swallow of the year to boot, plus a peregrine. Contentment inducing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/598-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 17:59:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/598-2/</guid>
      <description>Flock of fieldfares at Pemberely</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/586-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 13:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/586-2/</guid>
      <description>The mad thing is, now that we have all become hunter-gatherers again, my wife and I are going into shops more than we ever normally would. While we are not completely out of staple goods, we are finding it nigh on impossible to restock them.
Our village farm shop are being brilliant at supplying fresh produce and dairy goods. And we are still getting our weekly veg box. Presumably the panic-buyers will at some point run out of space in which to stockpile?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/581-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 06:06:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/581-2/</guid>
      <description>Don’t try this at home&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/577-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 16:23:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/577-2/</guid>
      <description>As an IndieWeb newbie I am very much still getting to grips with many aspects of applying the principles to my Wordpress blog. I had been struggling with how to implement reply-contexts until I came across this article by Chris Aldrich where he explains very clearly how to use the Post Kinds plugin. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t discovered the Response Properties box available in the post editor up until this point, but now I have I can show neat looking links, excerpts and author details for anything that I am replying to or commenting on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/562-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 12:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/562-2/</guid>
      <description>Re struggling to write, the paradox is that it is at times like the last week or so when I want to write more. There is so much going on, so much to assimilate and adapt to, and yet actually distilling the jumble of thoughts and reactions is hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/549-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 11:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/549-2/</guid>
      <description>The normally busy A303 at 8am on Friday. Felt like I was in a John Wyndham novel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/544-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 07:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/544-2/</guid>
      <description>I have found it hard to write this week. Anxiety, tiredness and addressing the banal have consumed any time or energy that I might otherwise have had to write. Thoughts have passed through my head and some I have even jotted down, but putting them together into something coherent has felt beyond my reach.
The beginning of the week was not easy. My wife and I are both self-employed and what with a lack of financial help from the government and the start of the lockdown, to say my anxiety went through the roof is not an overstatement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/542-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 05:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/542-2/</guid>
      <description>Heard my first Blackcaps of the year singing over the last couple of days. Still no swallows - with any luck they’ll turn up over the weekend. Bluetits still busy in the birdbox - don’t think they are building yet, a bit early. The robins seem to have been ousted from their nest box by a wren. They built their nest but a few days ago I realised that a wren was coming and going.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/532-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 13:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/532-2/</guid>
      <description>The lockdown does _not_ mean it is ok to drive down the middle of the road.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/526-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 20:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/526-2/</guid>
      <description>Benjamen Walker, who’s Theory of Everything podcast is one of my regular listens, has started a new series called Social Distance Learning - a wry look at the Coronovirus pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying out Signal as a secure cross-platform messaging app...</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/trying-out-signal-as-a-secure-cross-platform-messaging-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 15:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/trying-out-signal-as-a-secure-cross-platform-messaging-app/</guid>
      <description>I and a friend were recently trying out Signal as a secure cross-platform messaging app, something to use for group chats where not everyone is using iMessage. I had heard good things about it and this was largely born out in our trial. And yet…
Given that it is privacy conscious people who likely to be drawn to it, why does Signal insist on notifying other users who have you in their contacts list that you have joined and vice versa?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The weekend has arrived...</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/the-weekend-has-arrived/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 07:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/the-weekend-has-arrived/</guid>
      <description>The weekend has arrived not a moment too soon. While there are a some practicalities to sort out I feel that some serious downtime is needed after a pretty draining week.
I am going to keep my news intake to the bare minimum. Go for a run. Maybe two. Watch a film. Read. Perhaps even a bit of gaming. Get out into the garden. And any of this could be on my own or with my family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For the lexophile...</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/for-the-lexophile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 19:50:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/for-the-lexophile/</guid>
      <description>For the lexophile, this episode of The Allusionist will calm the mind in troubled times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The number of people in our village...</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/the-number-of-people-in-our-village/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 20:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/the-number-of-people-in-our-village/</guid>
      <description>The number of people in our village who have offered to run errands is impressive. It’s really heartening to see. So we have some offering to shop for groceries, or go to the Post Office, someone who works in the local pharmacy who can collect and deliver prescriptions and the local farm shop are going to prepare frozen meals for those that need them. Good to see such community spirit!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On further reflection...</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/on-further-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 13:24:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/on-further-reflection/</guid>
      <description>On further reflection it is probably for the best that we can’t get grocery deliveries online, as we are able to go out and hopefully it is those who need to self-isolate who are booking up the delivery slots. However, the cynic in me suspects that is not the case.
A business just down the road that supplies pubs and restaurants expects to last no more than a week, now that demand has disappeared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So far the Coronavirus has had little impact...</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/so-far-the-coronavirus-has-had-little-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 21:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/so-far-the-coronavirus-has-had-little-impact/</guid>
      <description>So far the Coronavirus has had little impact on us here in the south west of the UK. Schools are still open for the time being and we are largely able to work without making too many adjustments (so far).
What has become apparent just today is the effect of panic buying. We get our groceries delivered and on the back of a chance remark from someone we checked on the availability of delivery slots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/479-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 19:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/479-2/</guid>
      <description>Your query about a web player &amp;hellip; would Song.link fit the bill?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Victoria plum tree is covered in buds so am hoping for a good crop this year...</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/our-victoria-plum-tree-is-covered-in-buds-so-am-hoping-for-a-good-crop-this-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 16:53:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/our-victoria-plum-tree-is-covered-in-buds-so-am-hoping-for-a-good-crop-this-year/</guid>
      <description>Our Victoria plum tree is covered in buds so am hoping for a good crop this year. Yesterday I spotted a pigeon happily devouring them so shooed it away. Last year we didn’t get a single fruit for the same reason. I’m glad I saw the pigeon as it prompted me to get some netting over said tree in order to prevent further loss of blossom. Me - 1, pigeons - 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/12-march-2020-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 20:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/12-march-2020-2013/</guid>
      <description>NetNewsWire - never used any previous iterations of it before. Loaded it onto my phone this week. Clean and simple interface. Fast loading. Easy to use. Easily beats any other RSS readers I’ve used. On my home screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The birds are getting very busy...</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/the-birds-are-getting-very-busy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 06:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/the-birds-are-getting-very-busy/</guid>
      <description>The birds are getting very busy in our garden. All three nest boxes have had attention of some sort.
A pair of robins are nesting in one while a pair of blue tits seem very interested in another, spending a lot of time checking it out. The final box has been visited by great tits although I’m not confident yet that they will use it.
And the song thrush still sings on every morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great win for Australia in the Women&#39;s T20 World Cup...</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/great-win-for-australia-in-the-womens-t20-world-cup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 11:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/great-win-for-australia-in-the-womens-t20-world-cup/</guid>
      <description>Great win for Australia in the Women’s T20 World Cup. Not the nail-biter I was hoping for and disappointing for India, but a splendidly emphatic show from Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A few weeks back I mentioned seeing...</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/a-few-weeks-back-i-mentioned-seeing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 09:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/a-few-weeks-back-i-mentioned-seeing/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks back I mentioned seeing what I thought was a Barn owl . Since then, I am really pleased to have heard from two other people who have seen it, including being spotted hunting in a field not far from us. This is exactly what I have been hoping for - that it was finding prey in some of the rough grazing pasture around us.
As the evenings lengthen I hope to be able to get out around dusk and watch for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A real shame to see England knocked out...</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/a-real-shame-to-see-england-knocked-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 21:02:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/a-real-shame-to-see-england-knocked-out/</guid>
      <description>🏏A real shame to see England knocked out of the Women’s T20 World Cup in this way. But them’s the rules.
However, now that Australia have beaten South Africa, I shall look forward to the Australia vs India final. And Poonam Yadav doing her thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woke in the night to the sound of wind lashing rain...</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/woke-in-the-night-to-the-sound-of-wind-lashing-rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 08:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/woke-in-the-night-to-the-sound-of-wind-lashing-rain/</guid>
      <description>Woke in the night to the sound of wind lashing rain against the window - I don’t think I have ever heard it quite so loud before. Got up this morning to find the rain has moved through and the gales have subsided. Quite the contrast.
I have been trying to bring some sort of meditation/mindfulness practice into my daily routine, but lately I have let it slip. Work, CBT and some minor medical issues have been tiring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Having moved my blog to Wordpress, the first task</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/having-moved-my-blog-to-wordpress-the-first-task/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 21:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/having-moved-my-blog-to-wordpress-the-first-task/</guid>
      <description>Having moved my blog to Wordpress, the first task was to choose an IndieWeb-friendly theme. Over at IndieWeb.org there is advice aplenty on what themes work well - I won’t pretend to understand it all yet. I have used Autonomie by Matthias Pfefferle. I like it’s minimalist look - no doubt some tinkering will occur.
The second task was to find a way to easily post to the blog without involving the ghastly Wordpress app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/299/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 21:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/299/</guid>
      <description>For the past few months my blog has been hosted on Micro.blog. I really like the frictionless nature of using it. I mentioned this in a post in which I also said that I was done with Wordpress. So why have I been fiddling around with a self-hosted Wordpress site for my blog for the last week?
Firstly, when I said I was done with Wordpress I was referring to Wordpress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/268/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 13:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/268/</guid>
      <description>I like days like this at the tail end of winter. Temperature up to 14C, a few trees starting to blossom and hawthorn coming into leaf in the hedges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/138/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 13:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/138/</guid>
      <description>🏏Have enjoyed the SA vs Eng series - good games overall. Now looking forward to the Women&amp;rsquo;s T20 World Cup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/137/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 11:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/137/</guid>
      <description>When I decided to write about my experience with mental illness I didn’t really have in mind how much or how often I would share my thoughts. It was a case of have a go and see where it led. What I definitely hadn’t given consideration to was what, and if, to write when I am not feeling so great.
Part of the exercise was about being honest about the experience, and it goes without saying that a big part of most mental illness is not feeling too good about yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/136/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 10:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/136/</guid>
      <description>🎵 listening to… Holocene - Bon Iver</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/135/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 10:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/135/</guid>
      <description>Just in case you wondered… How the Met Office chooses storm names in the UK and Ireland</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/134/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 18:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/134/</guid>
      <description>One reason I enjoy this time of year is the way bird song gathers pace. It is a long lead in before it might be called the dawn chorus, although when exactly that starts is a moot point. In my mind it is when Blackbirds start singing in numbers. Great tits are one of the earliest to start - often within the first two weeks of the year I will hear the joyous monotony of their song.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/133/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 14:22:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/133/</guid>
      <description>Plan A was to go and do a bird survey this morning. Storm Ciara has rather put paid to that. Not that I am averse to being out in inclement weather but there are limits. Plus the practicalities of trying to see and count birds in rain and gales&amp;hellip;
So to Plan B. Stay indoors, enjoy a roast with my family for lunch and recharge from a demanding week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/132/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 05:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/132/</guid>
      <description>I had a text from my bank telling me that from time to time, when I pay using contactless I will be asked to enter my PIN. Just to make sure it’s really me.
Next year, I imagine that when I enter my PIN, I will be occasionally asked to sign a small piece of paper - just to check that it really is me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/131/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 22:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/131/</guid>
      <description>So long 🇪🇺. For now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/130/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 06:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/130/</guid>
      <description>Session three of my CBT course this week. I was recommended for what they call High Intensity CBT and intense it most certainly is. For someone who’s sleep is not the best, this is one way to get a solid night’s rest. When I received confirmation of the course, I knew it would be demanding, and I also knew that I didn’t really know just how demanding. I just hope I have the wherewithal to see it to its conclusion and come away with some tools to help improve my mental health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/129/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 06:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/129/</guid>
      <description>🏏 Very happy to see England win the 4th Test against SA and win the serie 3-1. And good to see Mark Wood come back into the side and have such an impact, after all his injury problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/128/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 06:27:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/128/</guid>
      <description>The sun is now rising before 8am - another mental milestone in the lengthening of daylight. Not that I would know, as the sky has been dominated by thick stratus cloud, and I’ve not seen the sun at all for several days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/127/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 19:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/127/</guid>
      <description>Mental health care postcode lottery ‘is risking lives’ - this article in the Guardian rather bears out what I discovered about access to NHS Talking Therapies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/126/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 20:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/126/</guid>
      <description>Mmmm, new notebook. First time I’ve tried one of these.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/125/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 19:38:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/125/</guid>
      <description>Listening to The Infinite Monkey Cage last week, I learnt that both rats and apes laugh. A quick search for laughing gorillas turned up this video of a young gorilla being tickled. I think I will save the link for moments when I need a good laugh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/124/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 12:23:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/124/</guid>
      <description>🏏 Another good win for England making it 2-1 for the series in SA. Some very good stuff coming from England in this game. A century each for Stokes &amp;amp; Pope, a fivefer for Bess, and 4 wkts for Root - I hear he’s also not bad with the bat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/123/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 08:52:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/123/</guid>
      <description>A dry frosty morning always seems to get the woodpeckers drumming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/122/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 08:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/122/</guid>
      <description>A second morning of frost. Looking out across the fields from our garden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/121/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 10:57:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/121/</guid>
      <description>Pre-sunrise run. First one in ages - forgotten how good it feels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/120/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 07:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/120/</guid>
      <description>First daffodils in flower in our village.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/119/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 15:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/119/</guid>
      <description>For the last 2 years or so I have been involved in conducting wetland bird surveys on the Somerset Levels. I have taken a break from it for a few months, while I get my head around the mental health issues I&amp;rsquo;ve been dealing with. Today however, I got back to it as I have been feeling ready to do so. Counts take place once a month on specified dates to enable coordination and today&amp;rsquo;s is the most important of the year as it coincides with the International Waterbird Census.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/118/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 17:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/118/</guid>
      <description>Moonset yesterday morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/117/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 05:31:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/117/</guid>
      <description>On Monday I will have my first Cognitive Behavioural Therapy appointment. When I was referred back in August I was told it was a six month waiting list - such is the NHS.
What I didn’t realise at the time was how lucky I am to have access to this therapy at all. Talking with a friend a couple of months ago, I learnt that they had no access to NHS Talking Therapies simply because of the NHS Trust they come under.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/116/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 07:50:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/116/</guid>
      <description>The asymmetry of sunrise/sunset times means that while sunset is getting later by the minute each day, sunrise is resolutely sticking around 08:15 and has done so since about the shortest day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/115/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 15:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/115/</guid>
      <description>🏏 Ben Stokes does it again and takes the last 3 wickets to win against SA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/114/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 20:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/114/</guid>
      <description>Back to work today and felt good for it, so the holiday break must have done its work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/113/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 20:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/113/</guid>
      <description>Needed to see the sea. A walk along the coast path near Sidmouth. Gave the dog a ride when he got tired. Stood on the beach. Threw pebbles into the waves. Sat on a bench in the sunshine and enjoyed coffee and chocolate brownies from the Clocktower Cafe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/112/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 14:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/112/</guid>
      <description>Maintaining and improving my general fitness has become more important as I make my way through my forties. Clearly, the top priority in this situation is to buy a new gadget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/111/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 20:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/111/</guid>
      <description>8am today, a Song thrush was singing from a tree just beyond our garden. Not its sub-song as might be expected at this time of year, but full song. Fantastic to hear it - felt like a spring morning. A good way to start the New Year. Have a listen - also a Robin singing and a scolding Blue Tit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/110/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 19:12:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/110/</guid>
      <description>An early start to go and see my parents. The murkiest of days, but comparatively quiet traffic-wise. Over the old Severn Bridge and up through the Forest of Dean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/109/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/109/</guid>
      <description>It hasn&amp;rsquo;t been easy to admit that in order to be able to make a return to doing longer walks we will have to leave the dog at home. But it is also a relief to do so. I have missed doing more strenuous walks on a regular basis and am conscious that I am not as fit as I&amp;rsquo;d like to be. The dog still gets his walks, plus gets to sleep by the woodburner while we are off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/108/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 06:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/108/</guid>
      <description>6:30am. I’ve just stepped outside. It’s perfectly still and clear. No moon, bright stars. A hint of lighter sky in the east. I can hear one or two cars out on the main road and a lone satellite is moving overhead. The wood burner is lit, cups of tea are made. Merry Christmas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/107/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 18:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/107/</guid>
      <description>📺 Watched the final episode of His Dark Materials last night. A high quality production but I think the series could have done with some editing - maybe down to six episodes. Still some of the best TV I’ve seen in a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/106/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 19:48:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/106/</guid>
      <description>📚 Current winter reading - Jonathan Strange and Mr Norrell by Susanna Clarke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/105/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 20:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/105/</guid>
      <description>One of those weird December days that seem to swallow up time. Off work recovering from a sickness bug, filthy weather, writing out Christmas cards, sleeping, and a dash to the shops for some groceries. I shall be glad for the routine of a normal working day tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/104/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 19:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/104/</guid>
      <description>“Dealing with fear, shame and vulnerability will never take us into a comfortable place, but it will take us to a courageous place.”  David Johnson, writes about self-worth and vulnerability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/103/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 13:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/103/</guid>
      <description>🎥 Watched Rogue One last night. Good fun, like The Dirty Dozen in space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/102/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 05:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/102/</guid>
      <description>A broken nights sleep checking in on the election results and realising we have 5 years of Boris ahead of us is not the most auspicious start to a Friday. If I were superstitious I might place some significance on it being the 13th.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/101/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 20:12:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/101/</guid>
      <description>A very bright and clear full moon tonight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/100/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 09:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/100/</guid>
      <description>Morning dog walks are now pre-sunrise which makes for some nice skies when there is broken cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/99/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 19:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/99/</guid>
      <description>It has been 8 weeks now that I have been taking antidepressants for my Social Anxiety Disorder. I was initially sceptical about trying them but ultimately concluded that it was worth a shot. Fortunately I got few side effects - nausea for a couple of weeks, and some very vivid and surreal dreams. Of the many possible side effects listed I note one is that you might feel ‘too happy’!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/98/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 11:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/98/</guid>
      <description>Oak Trees, iPhone, Filmborn, Fujicolor 160NS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/97/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 09:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/97/</guid>
      <description>🎙 I SPY - a new podcast about real life spies that I am enjoying. The first episode, about Jonna Mendez and her work in the CIA, is a fascinating story and worth a listen, even if just to learn that she held the job title of Chief of Disguise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/96/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 06:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/96/</guid>
      <description>At the weekend we watched Arrival. It has been on my list of films to see and happened to be on TV. A really thought provoking film and for me the kind of storytelling when sci-fi is at its best. I will now have to read the novella it is based on - Story of Your Life by Ted Chiang.
Funnily, I was thinking about Bladerunner 2049 - another of Denis Villeneuve&amp;rsquo;s films, after reading Colin Walker’s post about watching it on his phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/95/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 07:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/95/</guid>
      <description>🏏 So Root did go on to score a second century. Eng 476 all out. A draw the most likely outcome?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/94/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 07:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/94/</guid>
      <description>🏏 Eng now a more respectable 269&amp;frasl;5 in reply to NZ. And a century each for Burns and Root! Still a way to go, so hoping they don’t lose wickets quickly. Just need Root to hang on to his - maybe another hundred?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/93/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 06:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/93/</guid>
      <description>🏏 A shaky start for Eng in reply to NZ’s 375. 39-2 at the end of play and Rory Burns surviving two chances not an encouraging start, so fingers crossed for tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/92/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/92/</guid>
      <description>I mentioned a few days ago that I was trying out a note-taking/markdown app called Joplin. I had not heard of it before, but I had read a short review of it and thought it sounded worth a go.
So far I like it. The UI of both the iPhone and Mac apps could do with some polish but are elegant enough. Not pretty but get the job done.
What I do like is the following;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/91/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 20:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/91/</guid>
      <description>🎵 Listening to Opalescent - Jon Hopkins</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/90/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 21:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/90/</guid>
      <description>🦉Am pretty certain I saw a Barn owl near our home last night. I was driving, and the owl flew overhead so my headlights didn&amp;rsquo;t quite catch it, otherwise I would have been certain. I would be delighted if it was, as I have never seen one in the 12 years we have been here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/89/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 06:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/89/</guid>
      <description>🏏 Eng well and truly beaten in the 1st Test against NZ. Class act on the part of NZ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/88/</guid>
      <description>📚Just finished reading I&amp;rsquo;ll Keep You Safe by Peter May - the first of his I have read and a lighter read before moving onto something more demanding. I enjoy crime fiction but I have to say, while his writing is fine, I thought the plot resolution was preposterous tosh. The big reveal at the end had even occurred to me as a possibility but thought it so ridiculous it would never happen!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Mental Illness</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/hello-mental-illness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 07:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/hello-mental-illness/</guid>
      <description>Part of me doesn’t want to post this. Shame can be a powerful aspect to mental illness but I have found reading about other people’s experiences so meaningful I feel compelled to share my own.
Earlier this year I was diagnosed with Social Anxiety Disorder. Or SAD for short.
I had never heard of the condition until this year but it is one of the most common anxiety disorders. I have struggled with depressive episodes and anxiety since my teens but have never been able to quite put a finger on what the problem was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/86/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 20:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/86/</guid>
      <description>In my endless search for the ultimate note-taking/writing app, I have been using Simplenote for a couple of months. Just found that on the iPhone there is a problem selecting text - when I try to drag the handles they disappear.
Did my usual knee-jerk reaction and looked for other apps. I came across Joplin and am giving it a go. Quite like it so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/85/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 08:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/85/</guid>
      <description>Am involved with looking after our community woodland. Yesterday, went to look at a piece of woodland left to the local parish council in someone’s will. The wood is only about 20 years old, but some older trees exist along the boundaries. Found this Hornbeam, a tree I rarely see as such a large specimen. I wouldn’t like to guess it’s age but so nice to see one this large.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/84/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 06:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/84/</guid>
      <description>Enjoyed Annie Proulx’s The Shipping News. Second time I’ve read it. And I’m sure I’ll read it again in the future. 📚</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/83/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 18:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/83/</guid>
      <description>On a frosty and foggy morning, the trees I photographed for their autumn colour look a little different a week later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging about Mental Health</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/blogging-about-mental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 05:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/blogging-about-mental-health/</guid>
      <description>I didn’t expect to be dealing with mental health issues in my forties. But nor has it been a complete surprise either.
I don’t know quite yet how I will go about this, but my intention is to use blogging as a way of exploring my experiences and to chart my progress. The internet can be a toxic place, but it is also where I found valuable information on the issues I am dealing with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/81/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 05:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/81/</guid>
      <description>Looking up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/80/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 21:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/80/</guid>
      <description>Enjoyed episode 2 of His Dark Materials. Read the trilogy about 10 years ago and I can’t recall all the plot details so it feels quite fresh. I see next weeks’ episode is followed by a new production of H. G. Wells’ War of the Worlds. That’s my Sunday night viewing sorted then. 📺</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/79/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 05:09:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/79/</guid>
      <description>🏏 Just waking up to catch the end of the 5th T20 between NZ and Eng and they have tied, so would you believe it, we have a super over! Déjà vu&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/78/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 09:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/78/</guid>
      <description>🏏 A good win for England by 76 runs and now down to the decider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/77/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 06:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/77/</guid>
      <description>🏏 Worth waking up early for the Eng v NZ T20. Eng bat first, and clock their highest T20 score of 241, and a lovely century from Malan. This is more like it 😁</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/76/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 22:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/76/</guid>
      <description>The 4th T20 between Eng and NZ starts tomorrow at the more sociable hour of 5am UK time, so I should be awake to listen to the commentary. 🏏</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/75/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 19:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/75/</guid>
      <description>Part of my morning routine is to take our dog out for a short walk. Being an old boy with arthritis and failing eyesight, he likes to take his time, sniffing his way around the route. It’s supposed to be a chance for me to look around, take a moment before heading to work. Often though, preoccupation with the day ahead means my mind is elsewhere. Today was the first sunny morning in a while, and finally the trees are showing some good autumn colour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/74/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/74/</guid>
      <description>🏏 Woke up this morning to discover Eng have lost the 3rd T20 to NZ by 14 runs&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/73/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 19:12:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/73/</guid>
      <description>A walk in the woods this morning - autumn colour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“”</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2019/11/03/2019-11-03-72/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 09:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2019/11/03/2019-11-03-72/</guid>
      <description>🏏 So, NZ win the second T20 against Eng, well done them. 1-1, and all to play for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/71/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 08:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/71/</guid>
      <description>🏏 A good start for Eng on their tour of NZ - and not a Super Over in sight. Missed out on listening to the commentary due to the time difference, but catching up on the details with the Test Match Special podcast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/70/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 08:02:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/70/</guid>
      <description>My first ever flu jab yesterday. Had flu for the first time in years back in February. Lost several days work and felt washed out for weeks. So consider it worth a go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2019/10/26/2019-10-26-157/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 17:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2019/10/26/2019-10-26-157/</guid>
      <description>Have been watching Life on Mars, currently available on the BBC iPlayer, and which I somehow missed first time around. Am enjoying the era-specific references, including a View-Master. I had one of these as a kid and had completely forgotten! Kids today don’t know what they are missing… View-Master Model G by The Passenger is licensed under CC BY-SA 3.0</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/69/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 14:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/69/</guid>
      <description>A wet Saturday afternoon. A good excuse to play The Lord of the Rings card game with my son.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/68/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 13:27:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/68/</guid>
      <description>Have been watching Life on Mars, currently available on the BBC iPlayer, and which I somehow missed first time around. Am enjoying the era-specific references, including a View-Master. I had one of these as a kid and had completely forgotten! Kids today don’t know what they are missing&amp;hellip; View-Master Model G by The Passenger is licensed under CC BY-SA 3.0</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/67/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 06:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/67/</guid>
      <description>Before using Micro.blog I had a blog on Wordpress.com. In fact, I’ve had more than one - all started with good intentions, but each has run aground. One reason is Wordpress itself. It is so feature rich that it would get in the way of what blogging is about - writing. And I’m not talking about being distracted by features.
I found using both the Wordpress app and website at best slow and clunky, at worst prone to freezing and crashing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/66/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 06:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/66/</guid>
      <description>Walked the dog this morning, just getting light. Grey skies and a cool NE wind. Overhead, the calls of migrant Redwings. Just a handful, the first I’ve seen this autumn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/65/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 09:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/65/</guid>
      <description>Making the most of the decent autumn weather. A walk on the Exmoor coast yesterday near Selworthy Beacon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/64/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 22:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/64/</guid>
      <description>October sunrise</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/63/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 06:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/63/</guid>
      <description>I am apt to wake far too early - sometimes an hour or more before I need to. During the summer I don’t mind too much but now the mornings are dark it’s not so easy. I am far too prone to start worrying about things, so I am trying out listening to music or meditation audio. It helps - the only thing is by the time I actually have to get up I can be just about ready to nod off again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/62/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 06:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/62/</guid>
      <description>A recent podcast series I have enjoyed is The Case of Charles Dexter Ward. Based on the H.P. Lovecraft novel of the same name, it is given a modern setting and presented in the style of a true crime podcast, neatly sidestepping Lovecraft’s writing style. Enjoyable hokum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/61/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 05:18:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/61/</guid>
      <description>How do you weigh a live whale? As a non-scientist this is what I admire about scientists - finding ways to answer questions it wouldn’t even occur to me to ask.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/60/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 04:36:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/60/</guid>
      <description>October sky</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/59/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 19:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/59/</guid>
      <description>The dry summer has lasted well into September. Funnily, it was early in the month that we used the wood burner on a couple of cooler evenings. The rest have been very mild. All change last week, with gales and plenty of much needed rain.
Yesterday we collected conkers. Have no use for them. Just like to look at them, enjoy the feel of them in the hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/58/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 19:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/58/</guid>
      <description>Leaving for work on Monday morning, a flat tyre. A wheel change, a trip to the tyre shop, half the morning gone, original plans scuppered, how best to use the rest of the day. Usually this leaves me feeling frustrated, stressed, guilty even. Not quite in control and my day wasted.
As it was I was able to catch up on some outstanding tasks; email clients, planning, that sort of thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/57/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 19:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/57/</guid>
      <description>Deleted my Facebook account. Not that I used it much, but in terms of getting rid of accounts where privacy is the issue, Facebook is the big one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/56/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 19:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/56/</guid>
      <description>Went camping last weekend. Gorgeous weather, colder at night now. Cirrus clouds made a myriad of patterns. A little time to stop and look around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/55/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 19:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/55/</guid>
      <description>So that’s it for another Ashes series &amp;amp; The Summer of Cricket. And what a summer…Ben Stokes, Steve Smith, Jofra Archer…
Perhaps, as well, the question of who can open for England has finally been answered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/54/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 19:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/54/</guid>
      <description>Stepped out into our garden early this morning. There has been little in the way of bird song recently, but in the half-light of dawn, I could hear Robins singing again. I enjoy the shift in the seasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/53/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 19:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/53/</guid>
      <description>Well done Australia on retaining the Ashes. Moments of brilliance from England, but not enough. Sigh!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/52/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 19:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/52/</guid>
      <description>Among the dramas playing out in the current Ashes series, one thing is beginning to emerge - in Rory Burns, England may have found themselves a true opener with the right temperament. Perhaps a player whose technique is not influenced by the short form game? As Barney Ronay says in the Guardian, Burns is ‘here solely on first-class red-ball merit.’</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/51/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/51/</guid>
      <description>Deleted one of my Twitter accounts. It has sat idle for over a year anyway, but haven’t been able to bring myself to get rid of it. This is part of my drive to stop using social media silos. At some point I will write about my thinking behind this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/50/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/50/</guid>
      <description>Nature never ceases to amaze…Barn owls reflect moonlight in order to stun their prey</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/49/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 19:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/49/</guid>
      <description>Beech trees - Larkbarrow, Exmoor</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/48/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 18:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/48/</guid>
      <description>I realised this week that most of our swallows have left. For the last few weeks the sky has been full of their chatter. Thirty or so, maybe forty. Now just a few stragglers. There is a poignancy to migration. Time moves on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/47/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 18:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/47/</guid>
      <description>I have long thought that journaling is a great idea, but it has never really worked out for me. There are various reasons for this;
 With a traditional paper diary with pre-dated pages there is pressure to fill that space. And if I lack inspiration it is easy to give up. I have tended to think that ideas should be fully formed before committing them to record. This is an approach guaranteed to fail - who ever has a new idea or train of thought that is fully formed the moment it occurs?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 18:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/46/</guid>
      <description>I heard swallows giving their alarm call over the field beyond our garden. A fox was making its way across the field - and it seemed that the swallows were mobbing it. I have never heard of this before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/45/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/45/</guid>
      <description>Test cricket is often described in terms of its ebb and flow, but this 3rd Ashes Test has taken that concept to the extreme. An outstanding win for England. Ben Stokes’ innings was an extraordinary display of skill and perseverance. Jack Leach’s supporting role at the other end was superb. I hadn’t actually planned on spending the afternoon on the edge of my seat…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/44/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/44/</guid>
      <description>After England’s dire performance yesterday, Root and Denly’s batting against Australia today showed how gripping Test cricket can be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/43/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/43/</guid>
      <description>I missed out on listening to the cricket yesterday, which was evidently a great day for Jofra Archer. Am able to listen today - not a great start for England but looks to be a fascinating day’s play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/42/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 06:45:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/42/</guid>
      <description>After being silent for most of the summer, our local Tawny owls have started calling again - a sign of autumn’s incipience. Heard them last night and early this morning, a welcome part of our soundscape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 06:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/41/</guid>
      <description>Why is it that on returning from holiday I have the strong urge to get rid of Stuff? Is it because I’ve spent time away, taking only the basics with me? And then there is the catharsis of taking a car load of Stuff to the local tip…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/40/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 05:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/40/</guid>
      <description>This view across to Coquet Island in Northumberland is my reset button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/39/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/39/</guid>
      <description>Watched Midnight Special last night. It didn’t draw me in as much as I would have liked, but equally I appreciated the light touch with which the plot was handled - no excessive exposition, thank goodness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/37/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 07:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/37/</guid>
      <description>Cup and ring marks on the Roughting Linn stone, Northumberland. They are between 3500 and 6000 years old.  The rock, roughly 20m x 5m, is hidden away in woodland. An ancient place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 07:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/38/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog. I have started various blogs over the years, most of which have fizzled out for one reason or another. I like the discipline of writing - I think it is good for my brain.
Probably the main reason that I have not managed to keep blogging in the past is because most of the ones I have started are on a single topic. Because I tend to dabble in one thing, move on to something else, and then come back, I often found I lost momentum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/about/</guid>
      <description>Trying my best to mind the gaps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives</title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>