<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strandlines</title>
    <link>https://strandlines.blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Strandlines</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a&gt;Stephen James &lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 19:15:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://strandlines.blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/04/07/update_hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 19:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/04/07/update_hugo/</guid>
      <description>Still trying to get my head around how Hugo implements RSS. I thought I was there but then realised that my feed is only showing summaries of posts and not the full content. I know I edited the rss.xml file so that full content would be shown, but given the above, have to conclude that it was the wrong file.
However, since then I read that it could be due to using a older version of Hugo, which is something I know I need to address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/04/04/swallow_arrival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 17:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/04/04/swallow_arrival/</guid>
      <description>Sitting in the garden enjoying the sunshine a short while ago we heard the chatter of a swallow and there it was, one of ours, on its favourite spot on the telephone wires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/04/03/my_week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 17:46:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/04/03/my_week/</guid>
      <description>Setting the clocks forward an hour last weekend should dictate that I have trouble waking up early enough. So as the exception to prove the rule, I have woken at about 4:30am most mornings since, which a week ago would have been 3:30am. Go figure.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been keeping my eyes peeled for more swallows but none so far beyond the lone arrival on Tuesday.
Thursday was exceptionally hazy with Saharan dust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/30/first_swallow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 19:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/30/first_swallow/</guid>
      <description>Beautiful weather today. Blue skies, warm sun and a warm breeze. And on that presumably Mediterranean airflow, surprise surprise, my first swallow of the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/30/double_bill/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 06:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/30/double_bill/</guid>
      <description>Watched two films over the weekend.
The White Tiger. I found it really compelling. Reminded me of F. Scott Fitzgerald in its portrayal of the wealthy, their careless use of privilege and the subsequent damage to those around them. Balram&amp;rsquo;s charisma made me want to root for him, but in his efforts to break away from poverty, his means-to-an-end methods render him no better.
Annihilation. Oozes atmosphere. The ideas explored are thought provoking as any good sci-fi should be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/27/covid_jab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 09:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/27/covid_jab/</guid>
      <description>Had the invitation to get my Covid jab. All booked in for next Saturday. Went for an early appointment to hopefully give me time to get past any side effects over the weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/26/anxiety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 10:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/26/anxiety/</guid>
      <description>Found myself in circumstances earlier this week that set off major anxiety. I should have known it would happen as the anticipation had been rumbling around my head for days. It was the full on racing-thoughts-angry-sweating-tight-chested-backed-into-a-corner-fight-or-flight variety. Carried on for much of the day so I was exhausted by the end.
What did help though was discussing it with my wife. She could see it going on so very sensibly suggested we take a moment to talk it over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 20:36:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/23/</guid>
      <description>Cardhop for Mac by Flexibits looks like a useful app but it has a half-eaten sandwich as an icon. Which is just plain wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 20:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/22/</guid>
      <description>Further to my post about the sonic boom, the evidence for the meteor theory stacks up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/21/sonic_boom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 14:27:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/21/sonic_boom/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday afternoon, out in the garden. At 2.55pm a loud boom up in the sky, just to the south. A little like the sound of the live firing we sometimes hear from Salisbury Plain, when the MoD are playing with their toys.
Except this sound didn&amp;rsquo;t stop there. It continued with a kind of stuttering, throbbing quality, like a whole series of lesser &amp;lsquo;booms&amp;rsquo;, appearing to move to the west. For perhaps half a minute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 09:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/20/</guid>
      <description>The topic of what to do about the next phase of life has come up a lot in discussions between my wife and I of late. Although, to be honest, this particular discussion is one that has continued on and off for the entirety of our life together. And the &amp;lsquo;next phase&amp;rsquo; is just the subsequent few years or decade following on from wherever we are at a given point in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 19:37:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/19/</guid>
      <description>I rarely use titles for posts. When I imported my data from Wordpress to Hugo all those posts without a title automatically received the distinctly unglamorous moniker &amp;lsquo;None&amp;rsquo;.
I could go through all them all and remove the offending front matter by hand. I have done so with a few. But I think it much more fun to set myself the challenge of writing a Widgety-Bash-Thingummy to do it all for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/18/</guid>
      <description>Looks like I won&amp;rsquo;t be getting my vaccine until at least May due to a shortage. I can&amp;rsquo;t say it overly bothers me as I am low risk and I&amp;rsquo;m certainly not going to burden myself with trying to get my head around what politicians are saying or not saying about what is behind the shortage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/15/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen into the trap of fiddling around with the code for my blog rather than actual blogging. Having moved from Wordpress to Hugo, as per my plan, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on IndieWebifying the site.
The most important aspect for me was to get webmentions working. I think this is working now. It did take a some joining of the dots for a non-techy person but I got there in the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/13/reply/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strandlines.blog/2021/03/13/reply/</guid>
      <description> in reply to: spring
Yet another exciting test post. Another sentence </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>